Up
lên
[music]
[âm nhạc]
[Applause]
[Vỗ tay]
The time for the feast has arrived.  The time for the celebratory meal has
Giờ thọ trai đã đến. Giờ thọ trai đã
arrived.  With solemn reverence, I pay my respects to the sick.
đến. Trang nghiêm con kính bệnh. Trang
With solemnity, I respectfully address you.  I take pity on my
nghiêm con kính bạch. Nương lòng từ sư
master.  I take pity on my master.  From the virtuous conduct of the
phụ. Nương lòng từ sư phụ. Từ đức sáng
monks.  From the virtuous conduct of the monks.  The child received their
chư tăng. Từ đức sáng chư tăng. Con được
portion of food.  The child received their portion of food.   With
phần thức ăn. Con được phần thức ăn.
reverence, we offer this offering.  With reverence, we offer this offering
Thành kính dâng cúng dường. Thành kính
.  Buddhas throughout the ten
dâng cúng dường. Chư Phật khắp mườ
directions.  Buddhas in all directions.
phương. Chư Phật khắp m phương. Chứng
Proof and blessing.  Proof and
minh và chú nguyện. Chứng minh và chú
blessing.  May my child be at peace.  May my child
nguyện. Cho con được bình an. Cho con
be at peace.  The children are well-behaved and good students.   The children are well-
được bình an. Chăn ngoan và học giỏi.
behaved and good students.  Blessed by the Triple Gem
Chăn ngoan và học giỏi. Được tam bảo gia
.  Blessed by the Triple Gem.  After attaining
trì. Được tam bảo gia trì. Sau đắc thành
enlightenment, after attaining enlightenment, I
chánh giác, Sau đắc thành chánh giác,
would like to offer this again.  I would like to offer this donation
con lại xin cúng dâng. Con lại xin cúng
to the Bodhisattvas.  To the
dường đến các đức Bồ Tát. Đến các đức Bồ
Bodhisattvas, the gods, and the spirits.  All the
Tát, chư thiên, chư thần linh. Chư
Buddhas, all the deities,
thiền, chư thần linh cùng gia tiên tiền
and our ancestors.  The moon is
tổ cùng gia tiên tiền tổ. Nguyệt tất cả
blessed with the power of the Three Jewels, receiving
oai lực tam bảo nương oai lực tam bảo
sustenance and diligently striving.  With self-cultivation and diligent practice, one can find
thọ thực và tinh tấn. Có tự và tấn tu
peace and happiness.  Practicing asceticism brings peace and happiness.
hành được an vui. Tu hành được an vui.
Thank you.
Con xin được cảm ơn. Con xin được cảm
Thank you.  Above the master of the monks.  Above the
ơn. Trên sư phụ chư tăng. Trên sư phụ
Venerable Master, the monks, and the Buddhist laypeople.  Together with fellow
chư tăng cùng cô bác Phật tử. Cùng cô
Buddhist devotees.  Volunteers and
bác Phật tử. Các anh chị tình nguyện và
volunteers, and everywhere you look, there are
các anh chị tình nguyện và khắp các nhân
opportunities.  And through all circumstances, they cared for the
duyên. Và khắp các nhân duyên chăm cho
child, feeding and drinking.  Take care of feeding your child.  Studying and practicing
con ăn uống. Chăm cho con ăn uống. Học
this virtue will bring good results.  Studying and practicing this virtue will bring good results.
hành quả tu này. Học hành quả tu này.
Homage to the Buddha Shakyamuni.  Homage to the
Nam mô Phật Bổn Sư Thích Ca Mâu Ni. Nam
Buddha Shakyamuni.
mô Phật Bổn sư Thích Ca Mâu Ni.
[music]
[âm nhạc]